The all-new adventures
Atlantis: Milo's Return is a fantasy, animation, science
fiction film directed by Victor Cook.
Milo and Kida reunite with their friends to investigate strange occurances
around the world that seem to have links to the secrets of Atlantis.
Milo (voice), played by James Arnold Taylor.
Kida (voice), played by Cree Summer.
Whitmore (voice), played by John Mahoney.
Audrey / Nurse (voice), played by Jacqueline Obradors.
Vinny (voice), played by Don Novello.
Mole (voice), played by Corey Burton.
Atlantis: Milo's Return is a 2003 American animated anthology science fantasy action-adventure film,
made of unused TV episodes, directed by Victor Cook, Toby Shelton, and Tad Stones.
It is the sequel to Atlantis: The Lost Empire (2001).
The film received a direct-to-video release on May 20, 2003.
Originally, Disney was developing a sequel titled Shards of Chaos, but it was
abandoned once The Lost Empire was less successful than anticipated.
The released sequel consists of three segments, which are
"Kraken", "Spirit of the West" and "Spear of Destiny".
They were originally meant to be episodes of a series that
was never completed called Team Atlantis.
Some additional animation was done to link the stories more closely.
Cree Summer (Kida), Corey Burton (Mole), Don Novello (Vinny), Phil Morris (Dr.
Sweet), Jacqueline Obradors (Audrey), John Mahoney (Mr.
Whitmore), and Florence Stanley (Mrs.
Packard) all reprise their roles from the first film, with
James Arnold Taylor replacing Michael J.
Fox as Milo and Steve Barr replacing Jim Varney, who died before
the first film finished production, as Cookie.
This is Stanley's final film; she died months after production ended.
The film explores themes of submarine, atlantis,
cartoon, animal attack, villain.
The tone is thought_provoking.